









# **David Nangoh Najeme**

Information Technology Management Certificate – University of Cape Town (UCT)

Microsoft Azure Cloud Architect – Udacity

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Professional

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

Aviatrix Certified Engineer (Multi-Cloud Networking Associate)

CCNA Diploma, A+, N+, CloudU Certified,

ITIL v3 Foundation Service Management Certified,

VMware (vSphere 6), SonicWall Firewall,

IT Network and Infrastructure Engineer,

Diploma in IT Project Management,

Diploma in Business Analysis (Ongoing Study)

AWS DevOps & AWS Networking Specialty (Ongoing Self-pace)

# **Personal Details**

Residential address: Cape Town – South Africa

Languages: English (Native), French (moderate)

Cell phone number: +27 (0)78 125 9741

E-mail address: davidnajeme@gmail.com

## **Executive Summary**

An IT professional with a decade of work experience in IT Infrastructure and networking engineering. I hold a Certificate in Information Technology Management from the University of Cape Town and a Nanodegree from Udacity in Cloud Architect using Microsoft Azure. I also hold various IT certifications that range from AWS Solutions architect Professional, Aviatrix Networking Associate to IT Service Management. I am highly skilled, results-driven with extensive experience as a Network and Infrastructure engineer as demonstrated briefly below:

- Execute engineering tasks to analyse network systems, hardware, and architecture design
- Implement and maintain WAN, LAN, and VLANS networks

- Design and implementation of new solutions and systems based on the analysing network traffic
- Securing network systems by establishing and enforcing policies, and defining and monitoring access
- Provide training and guidance for the IT network team
- Maximizing network performance ensuring that the network resources are available 24/7.

## Qualifications

Diploma in IT – UK Level 6 | London School of Business & Research (LSBR) (Current)

Information Technology Management Certificate | University of Cape Town - 2020

Diploma in IT Project Management | ALISON, Galway (Ireland) - 2012

GCE Advanced Level (Biology & Geology) – Government Bilingual High School, Muyuka - 2004

**GCE Ordinary Level** (Mathematics, English, Biology, Geography, Chemistry, H. Biology) – Government Bilingual Secondary School, Muea - 1998

## **Certifications**

Certified in Cybersecurity (ISC<sup>2</sup>) | - 2023

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Professional | – 2022

Microsoft Azure Cloud Architect | Udacity – 2022

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate | - 2021

AWS Machine Learning Foundation Certificate | Udacity – 2021

Aviatrix Certified Engineer (Multi-Cloud Networking Associate) | 2020

ITIL V3 Foundation Certified in IT Service Management | 2018

Certificate in Fundamental Network Security | ALISON, Galway-Ireland – 2012

CloudU Certified (Cloud Computing) | Cloud University – Hosted by: Rackspace Hosting

Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) Diploma | LVMT Business School – 2008

## Skills

Interpersonal, Leadership, Motivated, Analytical, Problem-solving, Efficient

# **Technical Skills and Ability**

Cloud Computing: AWS Web Services, Microsoft Azure Cloud Services

AWS CI/CD pipeline, Cloudformation, Kubernetes, Terraform, Docker, ECS

Database: Oracle 11g, Microsoft SQL Databases, Microsoft SSRS 2012, SSIS 2012.

Systems: Windows Server, WSUS, WDS, Active Directory Services, Outlook client, Office

365, MS SQL Server, VMware ESXi on vSphere 6.5

Hardware: Servers, Routers & Catalyst Switches (Cisco), PCs, Dell Servers

**Networking:** LAN, TCP/IP, WLAN, WAN, VLAN, Ethernet, OSPF, RIP 1 & 2, EIGRP, BGP, DNS, DHCP, ACL, SNMP, NAT, Wi-Fi, IPSEC and VPN, PRTG Network Monitoring, Unifi Controller, Unifi AP, AWS VPC

**Security:** SonicWall Firewall / VPN, AVG Anti-virus, ESET Endpoint Security, ISA 2004, Microsoft Forefront

#### **Affiliations**

• Member of IITPSA (The Institute of IT Professional South Africa) since June 2012.

## **Professional Experience**

Position: IT Infrastructure Specialist

Current Company: Mama Money Pty
Duration of employment: July 2020 – Current

#### **Key duties include:**

- Responsible for the management of the company-wide internal IT Infrastructure
- Continuous recommending and creating the IT roadmap for the company
- Implementing VPN solution for the hybrid infrastructure
- Managing the Firewall, switch, access points and cloud controllers within the network

- Creating and implementing an Active Directory environment on Amazon Web Services and on-premises
- Designing and implementing group policies on Active Directory (AD) objects
- Administering JIRA Application and GSuite platform
- Implemented centralize endpoint devices patch management with Desktop Central
- Implementing and managing permissions and access to network resources
- Managing the overall acquisition of IT systems
- Creating and updating security policies for the company
- Remote supporting users working remotely and, in the office
- Recommending IT system and or infrastructure wide upgrade
- Introduce and launching cybersecurity awareness program within the business by liaising with cybersecurity consulting companies and disseminating cybersecurity newsletter once a month to all users

Position:
Current Company:
Employment Date:
Key duties include:

IT Network / Infrastructure Engineer Innervation PAN African Payment Jan 2018 – Jun 2020

- Configuring of routing and switching equipment based on the standard configuration
- Maintain, monitor, and supports the vSphere environment in the Data Centres
- Managed and administered the Office 365 and Azure environment
- Perform audit of Active Directory (AD) objects and user permission
- Ensure standardization, compliance, and enforcement of Active Directory security group policies
- Manage User Accounts on Windows platform (Creation, Deletion, Permissions, and VPN access
- Developed organizational units in Active Directory (AD) and managed user security with group policies
- Managed Group Policy Objects (GPOs) throughout the Active Directory (AD) enterprise
- Diagnose and resolve complex hardware, software, and connectivity problems
- Administer, monitor, and maintain Office 365 Exchange environment
- Securing network systems by establishing, monitoring, and enforcing users' and systems access policies

- Maintaining a 100% IT security policy compliance by configuring and testing the firewall and antivirus environments
- Upgrade and update data network equipment to the latest stable firmware releases
- Remote support of branch office users
- Capacity management and audit of IP addressing and hosted devices within data centres
- Launched cybersecurity awareness by introducing security newsletter once a month

# **Achievements**

• Involved on a migration project of Innervation Rewards client's (FORD) portal from Singapore to Innervation PAN African Payment's data centre.

Position held: Head of IT Department – (Network /

System / Database)

Previous Company: Innervation Rewards Employment Date: Jan 2017 – Dec 2017 Reason for leaving: Internal Move

**Duties included:** 

- Assisted in Projects with outsourced client as a Project Lead
- Designed and implemented a segregated VoIP and Data network for Innervation Rewards
- Managed the company's core business operations integrated with the SQL Database
- Generated monthly report to IT Director for budgeting and IT issues review
- Administered the Windows server environment (Domain Controller, Active Directory, File Server, MS SQL)
- Managed and approved all IT device procurement
- Compiled Monthly to annual IT report for the branch office
- Represented Innervation Rewards (Edenred) during our regional APAC IT departmental meeting regarding infrastructure and security issues and how to revamp all systems involved
- Managed and approved list of authorized IT devices and software suppliers
- Monitored and ensured software licenses compliance are up-to date

## **Achievements**

- Analyzed and recommended a revamp of our Self-Service Web Portal, which
  has given our clients an easy and efficient way to carry out online
  transactions on the portal up to an 80% client's approval record.
- Successfully recommended, configured, and deployed, a fully high-end cutting-edge server for the replacement of a lower capacity database server at Innervation Rewards.
- Database server availability of 99.9999% uptime record since the new deployed server was installed.
- Designed and implemented a segregated VoIP and data network for Innervation Rewards
- Gathered, analysed requirements, and improved on the reporting system; hence reducing the overall time to allocate funds to clients' profile during statement reconciliation for up to 80%.

Position held: Network / Database / SAGE CRM

**Administrator** 

Previous Company: Innervation Rewards
Employment Date: Aug 2013 – Dec 2016

Reason for leaving: Internal Move

**Duties included:** 

- Managed the entire servers and network infrastructure
- Administered the Microsoft SQL database
- Automated database back-ups through integration service scripting
- Managed and trained end-users on how to use SAGE CRM client software for clients' engagement with product increasing their output to over 70%
- Reduced server infrastructure downtime by 99.99% by configuring RAID on all servers for optimum performance
- Developed corporate-base security policy documentation and testing
- Designed and implemented a remodelled network infrastructure thereby reducing network outages by up-to 99.999%

Position held: (LAN) Network & System Administrator

Previous Company: Damelin College
Employment Date: Aug 2012 – Feb 2013
Reason for leaving: Awaiting work permit

**Responsibilities:** 

- Configured and managed File Server Print server, Domain Controller, Exchange server 2010, Anti-Virus Corporate Update server
- Configured and troubleshoot switching and routing issues on the network

- Managed Internet and network access control using the proxy server
- Managed ISA 2004 (Internet Security & Acceleration server Proxy Firewall)
- Managed Forefront Thread Management Gateway (TMG)
- Created and implemented file access control on the file server
- Performed weekly tape back-ups for the entire branch network
- Created and implemented an Image casting solution for automating and deploying software to all computers and LAN
- Managed assets register of all IT equipment

# **Achievements**

 Successfully deployed software and antivirus software across all labs and classrooms within a week using Windows deployment services